Another way to model time series is to think of
对时序进行建模的另一种方式是
the stock return hovering around in moving average.
将股票收益看作围绕某个移动平均线变化
As an analogy, imagine that you're walking at night while holding a lantern,
打个比方 假设夜晚你提着个灯笼在走路
a moth flies around the lantern,
有一个飞蛾围着灯笼飞
moving a bit randomly,
飞蛾飞得比较随机
but still following the general path of your lantern.
但是依然基本沿着灯笼的路线飞行
In this analogy, the lantern represents the average position.
在这个比喻中 灯笼表示平均位置
The moth's smaller movements relative to the lantern are the residuals.
飞蛾相对于灯笼的微小运动称为残差
The moth's movement relative to the ground is
飞蛾相对于地面的运动
a combination of the lantern's movement and the moth's relative movements.
等于灯笼的运动加上飞蛾的相对运动
In the moving average model,
移动平均模型
often called an MA model,
经常称为 MA 模型
we started with the average Mu.
首先是平均值 μ
To get the value at time T,
要获取时间 t 的值
we add a linear combination of residuals from the previous time periods.
我们加上之前时期的残差组合
In financial time series,
在金融时序中
the residuals represent the new unpredictable information
残差表示无法由过去的数据点表示的
that cannot be captured by the past data points.
新的不可预测信息
The residuals are the difference between
残差等于
the model's past predictions with the actual values that occurred.
模型的过去预测与实际值之间的差异
Moving average models are defined as MAQ where Q is the lag.
移动平均模型定义为 MA(q) q 表示滞后值
To decide the best value for Q in an MAQ model,
要确定 MA(q) 模型中的 q 最佳值是多少
you can draw an autocorrelation plot.
可以绘制一个自相关图
Correlation between two variables is a measure of
两个变量之间的相关性
how much one variable moves when the other variable moves.
表示当另一个变量移动时 某个变量的移动幅度是多少
Correlation ranges between negative one and one.
相关性的范围从 -1 到 1
Autocorrelation is a measure of how much
自相关表示当以前的值变化时
the current value moves in relation to one of its previous values.
当前值会如何变化
For example, let's say we noticed that the current stock return is usually
例如 假设我们发现当股票收益率的以前值为正时
positive when its previous value is positive, and vice versa.
当前股票收益率通常为正 反之亦然
Then, we can say that the stock has a positive autocorrelation with it's T minus 1 value.
那么股票与 t-1 的值之间是正自相关
Note how an autocorrelation plot is different from performing a multiple regression.
注意 自相关与多元回归不同
Correlation measures the pairwise relationship between exactly two periods at a time.
相关性一次仅衡量两个时期的两两关系
Multiple regression measures how a set of
多元回归表示一组自变量
independent variables collectively influence the value of the dependent variable.
共同对因变量的值有何影响
When we view an autocorrelation plot,
在查看自相关图时
we want to use the lag that contains highly positive or highly negative correlations.
我们希望使用的滞后的数据高度正相关或高度负相关
When we reach some time periods with little correlation,
如果某个时期的相关性很低
we can choose the lag to ignore those values
那么滞后值大于等于这个时期的
and any other time periods further back in time.
都会被截掉